...all right we're going to stop.
...thank you welcome to...suffer session my name is andrew clinic time the
group program manager for the app model team and the developer to the
developer platform part of windows I'm so excited to be here we've
been working on this...it seems like forever but
it finally have a really universal windows platform and introducing what the
...can do...half of the app model team who
...here I'm super excited to be telling you about this couple of things at
...seems pretty competitive we have an internal thing is
...who get the best school I again not prayer so...if
you like it let us know follow us on twitter and clinic so what's our
agenda first of all who this guy we
comput photos in the but microsoft kindly gives us pictures of representative
...will dress really well they have good heck and this guy
he's so excited to be here so,...why do we need that model and then what the heck
...that model and go through that and
...I like this guy so much here is get look?
Why do we...model he looks pretty hangs
...not quite sure and it's pretty important to think about why we need that model?
Because.
It makes the clicker work.
What this is why we're not shipping clearly so there
...are aiff?
So, ...why do we need that model and
yet windows is never really had a definition of what app is
you kinda know what it is when you see it but nobody can really put the finger on what it is
we space we started with the next...but what about how you install it what the
am you there's lots of different ways I've been a microsoft twenty years and I'm responsible for some of them and I
apologize for that.
How...still stay?
You know, what how long does your
aff wrongful that traditionally windows that's not really been a problem to as
...go as well as universal man we're running from my achieved through the phones
...hollow lenses how long does the whole graph law need to run for is
important things and how do you integrate the os how do we integrate with your applications?
And, then finally what can you and do?
So, the app model provides answers to these questions hopefully you'll like
So, what is the when the uw
p windows that model well it defines the act life-cycle and
...unify across all of the windows devices used sorrell...great demos today
...signed up so you can google your hologram but, it's important...be able to scale from
...will...reply to all the way up through a
...and xbox...the and pc and we want to do it in such a way that
...not taking the lowest common denominator if all you could do was run
...sense essentially what you can run a variety device on the pc, you know,
can be pretty happy you're not going to be happy, you know,...to build the applications you want to be able to do so
...model the scales what you want to be able to do if you wanted to run
...devices then at some point you have to make a tradeoff is like okay well shoot
...run on the phone there's only so much memory is available to me that...
great if I was running on a pc or high-end phone...showing the continuum those
phones are pretty cooling the amazing things like if I have a two-a-three gig phone
...I should be able to my app should be able to scale-up and do whatever
...do on that yet also go down to run on the five hundred twelve megabyte...
So, we like to think...app model is the kind of cradle to grave
...we install you we run you and, you know, eventually you'll get
on install hopefully that doesn't happen that often but, you know, is important to be
able to do that and one of the key things that we all forget?
How...to do is being...update your application
here we've had ways to install applications we've had ways to unsold but we've all had the update
experiences like well you're restart machines so you can update this program
well we'll frankly no never I never want to restart my machine
how can be able to update the specialise...thinking about distributing these action
the store I want that stores...what they I wanna-be kept up today I don't want to
wake up in the morning...of my pc and this is waiting with usc...saying well hey, you know, I want to
update this app that's the last thing you want to do when you install when you get up in the morning so?
The our app model inclusive all apps the
...windows have universal windows...and that's really, you know,
that's where we're going that feature and, clearly
...to do that but we have to run existing applications we have to be able to run phone
...windows eight-point one-x windows a microsoft but, we also have to run classic windows
...what the heck are classic windows apps that you and I probably know those as when
...you might know them is wpf...forms that dot net.
But, we try to come up with the term.
That kind of encompass the all those applications and really
kinda celebrated the greatness...many of us here why do you how we
...career frankly the...million programs are at the apps
...at the on windows today so, what classing those...classic windows apps?
And, if...this
...today but...introducing products and tenet price centennial is the ability
...convert your classic windows app written more everyone was so excited
...created the to the twitter tag for it so see w apps
...now I did so...at tag that some of the
reason ones were taken by things we didn't want so keen on so to universal windows...
These guys so excited he brought his dog.
This developer heats can hubby contains excitement dog looks a little
...must be said but so, when we think
about product centennial I'm thinking about how do we bring those windows apps and how
we bring them kind of kicking and screaming into the twenty first-century so they don't screw up your
machine so really it comes down to?
Defining and...model for classic windows x until now the really has
to be no definition of an app on windows I think bill gates wants
...somebody consumer money that they couldn't define what windows apples and,
frankly I think...to has the money so
we've been lots of attempts to do it but never systemic definition so that's
what it centennial sets out to do to enable you to run your applications and
you'll have to make some code changes in many cases hardly any coaches at all not go over
...second to
bring your application into the universe windows platform
...you can distribute...we can distributive...the mechanisms you have today.
Why now why do we that model
for desktop today in reality is windows
...we've all experienced we've all...technicals for colds a family member
...I didn't do anything and my pc the work now and?
His I've got...twelve...and I didn't do anything it just showed up.
Maybe they just showed up...the installed application that kind of change in
...we've all done that they downloaded something from you
have some of the websites where there's like sixteen buttons that say download
...of them the actually to download the act your trying to get so thing with the
experiences pretty awful from user perspective.
But, when you start...stony application assume is not chaining in some mal
...something terrible even if the app is trying to do the right thing?
The vast majority of windows wrought like why's my pc slowing down I
...couple of applications that...the...of my
pc is running it takes twenty-second longer startup I'm not even running
any apps is because of registry growth and fragmentation.
Think about how much.
Reads how many registry entries mace he local machine you
right kinda hafta...frankly...being here twenty years is
...awful,... controlled you have to write...local machine what does the
...local machine is loaded up as soon as you is levin the memory when you
please pc boots so...pc boo time is, you know,
a lot of it comes down to how big is your how is how big is
...local machine?
So, as...bigger and bigger becomes more difficult and becomes more a
...slower.
And, then finally.
How many you written on this tool is or try to understand...
How many you manage to do it one hundred-percent of the time
is almost impossible to do doesn't matter how hard you try you try to really,
really hot and, you know, frankly the sem maps that we don't try that hard
...but even if you are trying to do the right thing
it's gone difficult to do?
And, then finally n assign.
Allows custom actions.
And, any of this is where my
...come back to what me because I used to be the javascript pm.
In a full long long-time ago and,...like hey msi guys would be great if you
would scripts and...because like I...script everywhere well turns out that was a bad idea...was might, you know,
so, I get to fix that so ...executable code
...in the setup like nobody wants that nobody expects to get trying
to stall map and it starts just messing with...
And,...result your pc just...more and...the registry and hence you get...
So, what does the centennial
what the centennial bring what the app model...it bring?
The primary thing if you think about is the...is now a deployment model
...investing all of our efforts into making affects
via ultimate install across the windows ecosystem so essentially putting
...emphasizing
...go away we want to move to aspects were investing
...to provide the features that you're going to want to ensure that you can
install these applications and you can update.
... frankly provides a better way to install and...tool an update.
We're going to isolate the registry in this...
Now the following twitter this morning and the cycle my within the to
answer run the sandbox is going to be terrible can be super slow I think fake
...ives thanks for copying apple turns...not coping
...will not running around...assembles what we're doing is protecting
your application essentially from itself so if you write to wait he local machine
then that code still going to run but that your registry keys one actually make it to make
into hq local machine will be a store them application
...of specific to use such that when we get
one install run have to...all...all...registry settings across the entire
to the registry and we know that's never going to work hundred-percent we just go and take your hyphen just
deleted so from your code doesn't have to change.
What this means it makes it easy for us to update as applications install them and...
Enforces the app model policy...get on to the second.
Put the other thing the provides is once we start once you start building
...x there's a
whole slew of new features available to universal windows platform and I'll be talking about
the later that brings a whole new set of capabilities like integrating
...tama doing background audio maybe in a better
a better way and it's important you be able to take advantage of that
...your windows that so once you come...fx then heck you can put a background task
...if you want to go ahead you can start integrating with that so is
...help you take advanced to the new universal windows platform without you
having to change or your...you can bring your code along when it makes sense to you.
So, what is the...model policy...with the catch
...typically what I guess...going to do this but like there's going to have someone?
Your app it can call all the api is that it does today we're not
going to stop calling any of those api...it has the existing desktop
lifecycle if you app runs forever it will continue to run forever
so in many respects if you're if you're app is essentially just
...then you shouldn't really have to change anything.
What...not going to allow and...installs?
Things
that system components what specifically services and drivers.
When we when you install is that when you install
...it becomes almost impossible to update
this how many of us of like you're trying to updated driver without reboot
and we've been trying for a long-time to get that to work in reality we know
...work in terms of being able to make it easy to write a driver be able to updated
we also want to running as a driver doesn't matter how much we isolate you from the
registry
you you've got full access to machine you in the kernel potentially that point?
That is not what we want applications to
...that's not to say you can't take advantage of...the...you get
...is from windows update windows update knows transfer rollback...
rollback process for...much more complicated and frankly
...have a huge impact on...machine and rather than trying to make adtext the
...mandel and trying to deliver all different types of components
...saying look windows up...to deal with
...in those have to deal with services let me do that.
But, for applications we all
...two-run...just not going to just not going to deliver those
...services and...from that.
Second one and this is frankly the biggest perhaps should be the first is the
no admin elevation the last thing a
use ever wanted frankly was downs of usc...maybe the whole will
...also be usc fromthink about if you're going to put these acts in the stole.
The store updates at three o'clock in the morning...whenever the right
...time to go do that if it has to...you ac privileges it's awful...point
one the user experience is not going to water...frankly...have admin access then,
you know, you can kinda do everything you want to the device so
by not elevating to admin you get to installment per user
basis makes a low easy to install and this will replication the
great thing about fx...if you have more than one usual machine they've
...solder application and the second user logs and
then all it's going to do is basically just register a your application it doesn't have to
...again we have single instance...is going to be able to take advantage of that
you get all the benefits without the downsides of to...a do admin privileges.
The other thing...because we're doing is registry isolation
is impresses extensibility so some examples of that if
your application relies on other applications registering with
this for...for extensibility
...at the moment this year those other applications wagons can't come
from the store you can still do them you can still load them in your application and that's great and
we're very money we showed photoshop...is pretty done important photoshop we intend to
make that available later on this is not going to be available this year but if
...application installs browse help projects heaven help us if it does
...then those...work you can try and register them but they're going to
register the in the...what you think is registry...we
...rice's somewhere else in space for not going to see that your application is
the as registered for that we believe this is a step forward for use we
want to make applications isolated we want we want to make sure the single units
the easily updated and maintain will mean that people will
...a lot more happy and what more willing to
...replication because they kinda know what's going to happen when...from
and affects is going to install...never have to regret installing your application that...online
...might get some buyer's regret they don't like it but I don't like...known exactly the same
...they will before and this is vital so this is why this is why
we're denying these currently to ensure that?
So, tamar there's an indep session for a whole hour with john sheehan who is
...distinguish engineers around here somewhere will go into this in much more detail.
So, that's project centennial which is like bringing.
Classic windows apps into epics.
What about getting...what about getting a clicker works all right
...okay so you...user promises...
and but where do I get my application from well look we still want to store to be
the default place to do that from a consumer perspective is just...easier
more trustworthy place and the experience is significantly better they don't get
...give trying to get...download all manner of stuff the note
...from the app from the app stall...not going to regret installing
...but we also realize you want to have flexible deployment
in the preceding get where it was by having a store
...you them from installing applications so we're going to enable
you to do flexible deployment so that you can take...that you can side
larger applications onto pc onto a phone?
then finally the adtext improvements and there's a whole set from the epics improvements we
realize in the specially has universal acts become more complex
games of a stargate huge and
also with classic windows apps the current
...size the limit we have is too small so in which is ten we're supporting
...packages the great in
the hundred-fifty gigabytes that might take a walk download that but the fact is you can still you
can install lapped and take advantage of that so you start building great games
really start taking advantage of that or frankly in a photoshop...a to gigabyte affects the
...show this morning being able to do that is really important we can show you to do that.
Now getting your applications that's a great thing we have to be able to have to be able to
...and wheeler feedback about
our developer unlock situation and the feedback was well,
...kind of sucks is like,
you know, like ...phone...got a plug it into my pc I...a
...assigning my nsa...I...really want to have to do that and certainly if
...figure lab environment and I think there's
...are survey said the precisely zero developers love that...in visual studio
for windows development is like well hey I don't know if I can trust you after a month
...re-establish address so.
In windows ten...cool developer unlock notices setting on device.
It's just...just to control panel is the pc control panel
...point the settings that possess universe...so hey look we run...
There is so the key thing here it's just a settings that to
go...you want to go you want to go...phone...just get a settings and unlocking simon
the pc is a registry key so for enterprise customers they
could control they can set they can apple at registry key so that nobody can
set if they don't want the devices to be...sense the...should be able to control...
If you flip that also on phone you debugging now you don't have to debugging
every...can...a wifi so you can now completely cut the cord from a
phone perspective is super important lab environment so you can do all this stuff.
There are some limit some on phone is that you will once
...devon locked you can silo twenty applications a mpc is unlimited
because frankly it's unlimited for when thirty-two...so why would we provide
...limit for universe...we want you to go to universe laps we want to make it more difficult
...to build universal apps and is to...to build...
So, developer...is a big thing for us now
...of course in the building you have.
Didn't quite make it so the next the next flight will have this in fact
I think I think the control panel made it just doesn't do anything so?
So, it...ui that at model that model team is kind of
...new pixel teams we actually go in the team to do if you then...you...fall so but,
my view I give...some feedback on that.
as...become your...you have essentially infinite storage
...enough that people have to worry...pc's also become a small as often as
...of available storage is going down the certainly on the low-end tablets
...that little...piece the machine has what sixteen gigs
...doesn't have much to be able to install your applications on removable
storage is a key thing for us to be able to do and frankly pretty
...difficult to do it without removable storage whereas reply...come
...without...so we're going to enable you to install
a universal apps from affects on from...storage the
use the user will be able to choose from that from within the store.
Because if you think about the affects installation it doesn't give you any...injuring
...guesses set the default like look I want all my aunts to go through st...and,
then they can also move them and...the kind of classic vacation thing
...phone and you want to start taking photos...and you run
...space you okay well I just want to move all my aunts over tomy
...and you can move that after the fact.
The apps...enable removal...by default but you...because we
want the most...to be available to all uses all times but if you really,
really care about it you can you can turn it off so you can...tab of that and say look I don't want my
...be honesty codes the...when the on the st card
encrypted says I take the...car and, give it to a kale he's not going to be
able to go use the application because encrypted to my device.
And, we also take...in...put in the pc them,
... all bets are off right you can do so it is encrypted is also encrypted to ensure
isolation between applications that we enable isolation on device
and on pc using nt fs that's great we know the because I mean
yes you can format them is nt fs but frankly nobody does because the whole point you
...put it somewhere else so if it's fact rx...then icon
...that so we use encryption...even if application a managed to get
to application...folder all this going to find encrypted.
Data and this encrypted on a per
...on a per machine bases say we'll be able to your read it.
So, that's getting replications.
What can you applications do?
And, typically we think of this is multi-tasking
that precisely is not exactly multitasking but if you ask uses and frankly most
developers it's what can I do and how more how
...application run now one key thing that we've done
...in the universal windows platform is introduce resource management across-the-board those you
...phone developers will understand what resource management is the resource
...resource management essentially says well look I'm going to
say like if I'm running on a five hundred for make device then, you know,
you get hundred maybe megs maximum so that we can guarantee the experience
...can run and we will resource manage you so that if you go above that will
on the you will keep track of you from that perspective resource management also
tracks resources, resources that you don't want to apps from access
...camera one-time that's never going to end up well so it
is manages those resources are primarily?
Resource management is a web battery a memory and how do we provide
an efficient system such
that the user experience the device is...maintained a
...stay and, the fluid this is available that people expect and also
...applications to run and we...amiss scaling this...
such that we scale from one hundred and eighty megs on a five hundred twelve make phone form of three
gig phone or a forgave or sixteen gig pc then you expect
your memory caps to expand if I'm plugged in all the time
...care that...battery if you're building and app this primarily from on
t or primarily for a plugged in desktop the
probably the much care about our so again you can take advantage of that and find
out what's going on and there's...a whole session actually pre-recorded from that from...the...on my team
...chapel about exactly what that means to you and you have the mother
...spreadsheets was kind of three-dimensional chess of how this worksand,
but, it's a key thing...to consider?
So, once you have this memory control and once, you know,
what you can do that well what can I do from
...application how can I how can I run in the background?
And,...use in the user bp
...extended execution for
...applications now there's a whole session about this I kind of summarizes
in...kind of main scenarios about how you...applicationsthink about
it is the...let me finish saving my file.
Java fury showed excel up...running on the phone...on-screen lots of cool stuff
there now the way...all xcel runs on
the phone on the phone this continually saving...spreadsheet there is no file
save it's always saving up to one...to dropbox
wherever you chose to put it well if you have a huge spreadsheet and you get text...you
flip to that text message then excel is going to give...the
prior to this will get suspended which means you will...
So, what...invisibility for your app to...for more time to
...to complete what it's doing so this is across-the-board anybody can do that?
then the final one is what ical kind of turn by turn navigation scenario which
...is not just for that but if you think about you the map...is get the
...I star...I know it's going to go in the background the
match that knows is going to go in the background and,
it's going to essentially of what I want to keep running essentially forever but,
no, trust me I'll start running when I don't need to?
And, there since your
...telling the operating system when it starts up saying look I want to be able to running to run
the background so enabling this sets your applications could start doing this
that how many applications can run for how long will depend on the resources are
available...you on device on a five hundred twelve megabyte device or
an imc then that might not be very long at all but if you're running on a...deep the
hi m phone...pc then you're going to get a lot more resources a lot more
...guarantees what's going to be able to run.
And, then finally we're really expanding triggers such that you trig is
a great in terms of they run your code when it needs to so geo fencing is
the classic example or bluetooth beacons which are...session on later this week is
...if I care about I want to do something when I get home I don't want my
...running the whole time on the
...might be home so this set of gg offense trigger when the true when I get close
...the differences triggered...starts...a background
...for my application so my aunt runs when it needs to so.
The goal here is provided balance
...uses get the experience they want they think it's multi-tasking
...in reality it's not...providing real enough multi-tasking
such the users can get that now on hiring devices you get full
...you can go-go ahead and do that but we need to be able to scale down to
...devices that says if you talk to uses what they really think about
multi-tasking?
Is the app resume policy you talk to use a if something is if something when
they tap on the tile if it if it comes back immediately that pretty much is running in
the background that is the definition because frankly...the app is...the background?
in the universe windows platform wince...this app resume policy so
...all applications will resume by the...says that if you switch away from the application will
...and if this still memory to keep it in memory then it's
not running suspended them whenever you launch...application it will resume.
All windows phone eight-point one applications and eight and a point...and
eight-point one desktop...also have this resume policies is actually not a new experience which
is...making the default across the universal windows
platform with one key exception and that's the windows phone seven
or eight os they don't we really want them to
but what we found is the from application compatibility perspective
all these applications...assuming that they would always get fractions so
...we found...testing is...we turned on this policy
and those you outlaw of the applications crash...didn't...the way we
...to...you have windows phone several
...a eight-point...if you...p then.
This is something you think about
thinking about how your application is going to be resuming all the time now
there's implications...thinking about how you're going to load state and save state.
But, you really have to think about how you applications going to get used.
You think about this there's basically if you're
always going to be resumed if you if you've only got a single entry point from
alive tile.
So, you...you don't have a notification to have
secondary charles you have to worry about people we entering your app
but there are essentially two models for this you can always resume experience and I would
say the browser on phone or...spawn
...use this you are you expectation for the browsers when you go back to the browser
for you have five the browser...you expected to be on the
...web page you're wrong you don't expected to...back to some kind of mythical home for
...for your web for those webpages but,
for some applications navigating back to home is pretty important and I would say the
email as the classic example of this is if I temple my inbox the
icon I kind of expected go back to my inbox not
to the email that I was...working on now frank is
user choices your choices and application as the which because both of those
good models in...makes it you get to choose
one thing we ask you to do if you do resume bank two-way you
provide a wave for your application to get back to somewhere where
...feel comfortable I call this kind of back button and easier
...nobody can really remember
...two-a-three backs is like well...the heck was...I resume and application I
losses like ten minutes ago the likelihood of me knowing where I walls
we'll have to get back is pretty it's pretty difficult to do so I think the twitter
...phone does a pretty nice job this has...one-button...hamburger
...of different ui...to do this but think about when people are going to come back
into your application the reason we have to do that is that will unifying.
The navigation model across ...
So, you the backbone so today
...I if I stein application on phone and this is
...devil you can tell I'm not a ui design and I tap on that
...I click on that hopefully you can see in the top...I have the
...button highlighted on my phone which is always there so when...hit back and they'll take me back to
where I was of on the desktop when I'm
running a windows then the...is going to be in the top
...left-hand corner of my app that makes more sense if I'm running with
...keyboard the expected to be the.
Okay, so, when I when I go when I go back?
...the key thing it takes...back...
And, that that's what I expect the difference all
phone is when I hit back and I've if I've reached the end of the backs tackle might
of my application I hit back is going to switch me back to the application
...the stotsky whatever was before my applications now when I'm running in
a window on a pc that doesn't make much sense what is the application I
didn't really expect
...hidden back in one applications take me to another one so the
...button in windows run running in a windowed environment stops
at the application so if you re hit the end of the back stack then essentially is going to stop
going back within the application but the phone because you arcs usability studies shown this
that you people really love the backbone frankly way more than we thought they would really love
the back but they really, really love it and they expect to be able to navigate
around between applications using the backbone on that.
Now one key thing gesture continuum when I go
to continually we all kind of...is tablet mode right now is
the once I go to tablet...then I will get a
back button in the stop-off just like I do today on phones
...when I'm using a tablet like...joshi that lenovo tablet kind of expect that to
sort of work kind of like...so once I go into continue mode
into tablet mode then I will get back button which to work the same way as
phone does in terms of it will back you between applications as well?
So, as you think about the navigation...important...think about how people are going to get your
application there's also the task which is...people with switch to your application from the task which
...the in we...that's more of a car high-end usable
solo easier to get too now in windows, windows ten so expect the people are going to
becoming to application multiple different ways of think about that from user experience perspective.
As we build these applications and people start user applications.
Being able to provide an integrated experience
...the operating system whether other applications is really,
really important that traditionally axle mobile devices have
been isolated isolate is good...give brings a lot of value in terms of,
... I can I know the if I run this app it's not going to go mess up anything
...take dependencies from other applications but use want to get things done and
your often that means integrating with the operating system instigating with
...replications and, you know,
we took a step back here and said well okay like.
We think application integrations pretty done important how do how do you how we going to
go do this so we looked at the web and...what
...web teachers what...that url based activation.
Brings a whole bunch of simplicity it makes it really easy to
link for application replication be all we have to those url
...so if I want to integrate...
Amazon then is just like amazon-dot-com...what the of some ungodly length
...url...cut-and-paste it and just go ahead and do it so,
how can I do if I keep it simple?
Then it makes it really easy for people to integrate applications...see that the web today I mean how
many people how many...websites a completely isolated not
design to work with anybody else and then we kind of...and I history is the,
you know, what conti teachers and...be doing application of grayson with common
...automation since, you know, it ninety-three well,
you know,...a whole bunch of things but it did teachers?
Is that complexity kills is the...is incredibly ecosystem with application
integration available in calm but at some point it becomes too when
will the overate difficult to manage and people with
...less and less dependencies on each other so we want to build a web of...
So, again,
this guy that reallyhe's looking for web apps either is might be...so, a
web of apps was really allowing applications to integrate using the best
of the web so we want to enable url
based activation communication between applications and this is really key from a full
gramm program perspective like if I want to if I want to make a phone call with me if you
want strike me then I just have to...scott cohn...clinic and magically sky
pull launch and I do a...for gram so I can get my applications to do that
and we will see this with facebook use this a-law...the facebook sdk if you want to
war with them one of the challenges of that is like I could launch url.
But, if I want to get the result back then I kinda have to hacker...have to get the application the
...know what url to call me back home and it kind of
involves shared secrets and a whole bunch of frankly stuff that you...any with
pratibha kind of work but not really a great way to do that in ten with
...enabling that so you can actually get a return result so you can just like you can do...the web I can
...and application...give-me results...back so you can do
integration with applications and provide a great user experience and we even do
...far if you're running a window then that application you cold
...kind of bounty windows so the user experience...like look I'm calling from application
...application b but it's not like I'm seeing a sea of applications
show up again taking some of the benefit from the web and apply those replications.
Perhaps the most exciting thing that was foreground
background is the integrating with other applications is great.
But, he kinda lose the user to another application might not come back if I sent somebody to amazon
...probably just go off and, you know,
find out what the today's offer on will never come back to my app so,
foreground background enables you to integrate other
...application in of all of you to publish functionality from your app the
other applications can cool...application remains in the forward.
Now frankly this is something which we started windows phone...one for facebook
...integration but the people application in on the phone doesn't know anything about facebook
twitter...there's a facebook twitter application is on the phone so it
...that's those are the gets...use feed and those application can also go in and,
...contacts and what we've done is we've taken that design
...and made it available to all applications and, you know,
we...so much?
That we really...we made a big change because frankly we've done a good job of the building a
platform...not building any of our applications on in the
past is tania dependency on ourselves so...to app
...services the used across-the-board.
...people use apps
services extensively used focus on a I'll go to the little bit but...work with
...offices sky do that interactive toasts enable
...they call background services such that when you when you type in a
...online it just works on that photos for
...filters and...using this...can go and query
what applications of available that support particular service.
For example, the vibrant integration the joshi of what they do what they
...that service...the at manifest hopefully you'll see this the
...all I've done is defined an entry point and then
...service and say okay look I'm going to expose this at this is my background
task other applications can...that's your choice you don't have to expose that service
you get to choose how much you want to expand out and these...for voice, come on,
definition with capone you can see here is
...the command send name and you give it the syntax
ecbatana understands and then you just say what the target for that thing is
the app service so when joe was saying,
you know, send...a message...with link value of with them vaibhav
I'm going-to be late it was just calling the vibe app service in the background so this
have you can integrate with...very easily just by creating a background task in your application.
we believe the web of apps and apps...really going to enable you to build much richer and deeper
...provide away...users to engage with your applications more because frankly
...sausages...application then yet which is going to go up
...have...will be...that they can get to the raps easier.
...is not the only way that
you can engage with will uses the most iconic thing we've had.
Essentially since windows phone first came out is lifestyles live
...great and you we're.
Humbled in...the how much everybody is integrating with
...tiles but the...feedback we've...like, you know,
frankly this templates you provide two-s that kind of useless
...can't use them so what do you all do you providing background...the generate...
I'm sure the last thing that you want do...more get up in the morning is like
...generate paying example and try and get...less than fifteen megabytes and hope that the
user still going to work that so we're introducing.
In the view...bp adaptive tile templates
...a tall templates enable you to provide a simple xml.
So, that you...extend the existing templates...give you a
lot more flexibility how you can layout your tile now.
This is actually difficult talk through song of share this is my one demo my one piece of ui.
And,...itself.
Okay, so, this is application our team built
...injure a team build this and we're going to make this available...can use it so in
this sense enables you...one of the key challenges
...tiles like am I going to build this thing how do I design what I want my
tile to look like and how do I have any clue as to what is going look like so here
...have a really simple xml but, you know, I can go nuts here is that will
look,... now I get a lot more control over how everything however thing
...so here's a simple calendar here is...smiling face not the
his vain or anything but puts is pictures in demos and,
you know, male and...one of the great things about what we've done this releases
our built first...applications all using our
...platform so you have a mail at...has some pretty strong requirements of
what...might look...they want to be able to do that?
You know, our money off of finance app is like you
...currently to do this today they have to generate...and are the semi down from the
server all the using a whole bunch of compute our what you think about like if
you're sending down tiles these...hundreds of
...these things and our your bandwidth what bandwidth as cheap
is not free...not free to be end-user either in terms of, you know,
like to generate this the would have to generate a paying and...pins
...efficient but there are as efficient as a piece of text?
So, you can drastically reduce the map bandwidth you have to use
...that your tiles skills save you money it's
...make uses a lot happier because that now the data use is
...go down every month think about if you're a sports network and you'll following
...a...probably the worse right in terms of use sending score updates all the time and
you would generating things on the server think how much bandwidth that
...to use following three-four teams
...using here you can go from my ten twenty meg during a game
to me that maybe fifty sixty k so significant saving from that perspective.
So, you tiles a great.
And, this great way to engage with the uses the
action sensor is years was a huge...on windows phone and
...notifications is the ultimate way to really connect with your
uses if you want if I want to send a message to a particular user
...notifications the only way that I can actually deliver that on a per user
basis but as a result I end up with a lot of notifications so action
...is now coming across all of...both the phone and,
the desktop.
So, the same look and feel across the windows family it's
...to the user experience you on all of you will...on the
desktop it looks it has essentially the same behavior but looks slightly different.
But, what we're doing this time in is really building at the action...platform
says you have complete control over them so maybe you want to be able to delete
what's that all light one of the key request that we got was like well look I have maybe
have three messages semi live...says has a camera three and I swipe
...one of those messages one you couldn't do that before but now you can
...individual messages...I want my count on my life tile
to be in sync with...into...we really confuse...sense
...change trigger says you can take about you will know when the
users change something on the topon action...so they can swipe that away and you can do whatever you
...the appropriate thing to do the obvious one is keeping alive...maxus sentencing?
So, but, you can keep complete control you-can delete all your thing that you might say well
...twenty notifications maybe I just
...reduce that saying...you have twenty-plus notifications
...of them rather than taking up the whole actions and we
believe access centers really a great way combined with live tiles to really engage
...get apps them using your applications more and more.
that's engaging with...the final way to engage reviews is thinking about the data
and the applications that they use on the device and how can you integrate with those?
All in...universe windows platform
...introducing the at a common data store was going to give
you complete access to the context count the email
...messaging so-if you-can integrate with that says that if you want to write...cal if you want to
write...you go ahead and do that...be able to read from it you can go ahead and do that
now obviously the user is in control they can turn off access to application
...they'll be asked if they want to give you at
your app the access to these
...but it really enables you to build tighter integration and like,
for example, you know,
I want to be able to you if you look at the way that context link...
I can write my app right my contact store into the...automatically link such the,
you know, my wife, you know, you surely has twitter facebook and,
they all integrate into that and if it was if
...application they could integrate on that and all linked together
...you get a nice experience in the people application and then finally with email messing
...what now we realize we have to be responsible
here but I think we role love to be able to send
...messages but we also know?
There are people out there...messages the frankly...not doing it for the greater
good of mankind so that these are available
we starting...so we're starting...you can
...mission on this we are making available and we'll
...frankly looking to you guys to give us feedback on that and wall
be the right policy to do that so we're not going to make...the sm store available to everybody
up-front but we are we are enabling it and we're starting small...start with
...small companies and we'll expand that over time because we don't want, you know,
sms spam is...
...to...cost a lot of money
so we don't want that to happen we don't we don't want to make the experience terrible.
...windows platform you really want
...make it easy for all uses the get all of your applications and we really mean
all of your applications centennial enables you to bring your existing applications and bring them
to store with very simple changes we want to give you more flexible
multi-tasking says you can do more with these devices as these devices as...showed,
you know, you...view continue on the phone I want to be able to do
mole when I'm running my experience I want to have a unify navigation experience
since the I don't have to think like how's it going to work on...phone has going-to work on
the pc you can still choose to write an application that just runs on the phone just runs
in the pc but by having a common approach you can take advances
...concentrate on writing your application url
...app integration we really believe
...applications is going to enable considerable new experiences and then the
stall and search integration with...and richer
...maxus...now my session this is the first session
format model which you have.
This is spectacular slide the I'll take no,
credit for whatsoever but this is really kind of a map of all the I'm really kind of
warm-up that so.
...on my team is providing as I okay why.
If you really want to know of app x and deployment if you really want to know all the...details the
boxes going to a deep dive on that enterprise...distribution...
...actually going to be ignite so, if you if you want
...the enterprise than just wait till next week on what it online but,
john is here...we can if you do have enterprise app distribution questions I'm happy to take
those off with navigation when doing in windows ten
expanding on the information I...going to be writing that.
And, then
shown and put together the slides really going to go into.
The complete...life-cycle thinking about how does this
multitasking really work what's available how can you take advantage of that.
And, then finally thomas.
Is going to be writing shel and,
how that's you the thousand notifications action censor but really
going into depth from that and then finally quite literally finally if you're still here
on friday afternoon will be very happy to see you at the app services it is the
...session the friday so we do appreciate that
...the stuff and then the final one is tony's...to be providing a deep dive into
...of data...you code access to that so with super excited the
app model we believe it's...to be able to provide a significant impact
and what you can build and...excited...to be here and whip
...here for the rest the week so...showing up and the...my presentation?